brice.shatzer@gmail.com 319-239-2470

Brice Shatzer

www.BriceShatzer.com

Chicago-based technologist with a decade of experience building software for businesses of all sizes. Skilled in crafting both delightful user-facing interactions & pragmatic solutions, with a passion for the administrative and organizational processes around the craft of software development.

Tools & Technologies -

- "Vanilla" HTML, CSS, & JavaScript
- JavaScript Typescript / Flow
 React / Preact / Svelte / Storybook.js
- **Node.js** *Next.js / Express.js*
- CSS SASS / SCSS / LESS

TailwindCSS / styled-components

- Build Tools Webpack / Babel / Rollup / Vite
 Gulp / Grunt / ESLint / Prettier / PostCSS
- **Testing Utilities** Jest / Mocha / Jasmine / Enzyme / Karma Puppeteer / BrowserStack / Sauce Labs / LambdaTest
- CI/CD GitHub Actions / CircleCl / Bitbucket
- AWS EC2 / S3 / Lambda / DynamoDB

Recent Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer – W.W. Grainger, Inc.

October 2021 - September 2024

- Part of the Core Engineering team that was responsible for building, documenting, & supporting the design system and various other tools that are relied upon by various teams across the 1000+ person engineering organization. This team was responsible for saving over 5400 hours of engineering work during my tenure
- Worked primarily in React, Svelte, Next.js, Typescript, SASS, styled-components, & Storybook.js

Senior Software Engineer – PayPal

July 2020 - August 2021

- Part of the Checkout Integrations team that worked on the company's flagship service which handles \$100+B
 in payment volumes across 200+ countries for millions of active users a month
- Primary developer and point of contact for our "Pay w/ Venmo" desktop solution, enabling users to generate a QR Code that allows them to complete the checkout process via their mobile device
- Worked primarily in Preact, Flow, Storybook.js, & Express

Software Engineer – Onion Inc. | G/O Media

September 2017 - April 2020

- Part of the team that worked on Kinja, the CMS powering some of the internet's favorite sites like Gizmodo, Lifehacker, Kotaku, and The Onion; reaching 85-100 million active users a month
- Implemented & maintained advertising integrations which optimized delivery & tracking, ensuring high performance and reliability across the platform
- Helped migrate and rewrite our core platform from a Scala w/ Closure templates & Backbone.js to an Isomorphic JavaScript (Express & React) solution

Full Work History

Software Engineer

February 2016 - April 2017

Doejo - Digital agency that specialized in serving enterprise WordPress VIP clients

Web Developer II

September 2015 - February 2016

GoHealth - One of the leading digital health insurance marketplaces

UI/Front-End Developer

November 2014 - September 2015

Packback – SharkTank-funded startup creating a platform for digital textbook rentals

Web Developer/Designer

April 2012 - July 2014

Links Technology Solutions — Agency providing custom web & software solutions

Education